Guide to the Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection
The Wittliff Collections
Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection
1972-2011
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Shepard, Sam, 1943-2017; Dark, Johnny, 1940-
SWWC.106
3.5 Linear Feet
8 boxes
The Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection spans 1972-2011 and documents the men's forty-plus year friendship. The collection is arranged in five series: Correspondence, Dialogues, Photographs, Audio Material, and Video Material.
Scope and Contents
The Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection spans 1972-2011 and documents the men's forty-plus year friendship. The collection is arranged in five series: Correspondence, Dialogues, Photographs, Audio Material, and Video Material.
Series I: Correspondence comprises the bulk of the collection (boxes 1-4) and is arranged chronologically. The first letters are from the early 1970s when the Shepards lived briefly in England and the Darks remained in California. Because the two families lived together for many years, there are few letters until 1980 when Shepard began filming on location. The letters pick up in earnest in 1983 after Shepard left his wife and son and began a long-term relationship with actress Jessica Lange. For the next three decades, the two men kept up a fairly regular correspondence.
Series II: Dialogues is over 200 pages of typed transcripts of conversations that Dark and Shepard recorded in the 1970s and 1980s. Arranged in themed sections by Dark, the conversations cover a wide range of topics including relationships, writing, film, ageing, and friendship.
Series III: Photographs is comprised of photographs collected by Dark. Many are mounted onto notebook pages with annotations in Dark's hand. These photographs provide a glimpse into the private lives of the men. The bulk of the photos are of Shepard and Dark, but there are also images of Scarlett Dark, O-Lan Jones, Jesse Shepard, Sam Rogers (Shepard's father) and Jessica Lange. The photographs are in the order in which Dark arranged them, and each has a unique identifying number (001-178) assigned by the archivist. In addition to the numbered photographs, there are over 250 snapshots taken by Dark. Many of these are duplicates of the numbered photographs, but there are several unique ones including shots of Shepard on the set of All the Pretty Horses with Matt Damon, photos from Jesse Shepard's wedding, and more photos of Shepard and of Dark.
Series IV: Audio Material contains 28 tapes of varying audio quality. Most of the tapes feature conversations between Shepard and Dark - some recorded in person, some over the telephone. The tapes from the 1970s and 1980s form the basis of Dark's typescript, Dialogues, in Series II. All of the cassettes have been digitized, and there are listening copies available. Archives staff have provided summaries of many, but not all, of the digitized tapes.
Series V: Video Material consists of two items. The first is a VHS tape of home movies shot by Dark. The video quality is relatively poor, but the tape has been digitized and a viewing copy is available. The second item is a DVD of the documentary, Shepard and Dark, directed by Treva Wurmfeld. Access to this DVD is by special permission only. Terminology Notes for the correspondence:
ALS Autograph [handwritten] Letter Signed (AL = Autograph Letter)
TLS Typed Letter Signed (TL = Typed Letter)
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase, 2011.
Related Materials
The Southwestern Writers Collection holds an extensive Sam Shepard Collection (SWWC Collection 054)
The University of Texas at Austin holds a collection of Sam Shepard papers.
Biographical Notes
Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark met in New York City in the early 1960s. Dark married Scarlett Johnson, and Shepard married one of Scarlett's daughters, O-Lan, with whom he had a son, Jesse Shepard. Over the next several years, the two couples lived together in Greenwich Village, Newfoundland, and California; and through the decades, Dark and Shepard have remained close friends. When distance separated them, they wrote letters back and forth, beginning with the Shepards' stay in England in 1972, and then beginning in earnest in 1983 when Shepard left the family for a relationship with Jessica Lange, whom he had met on the set of Frances. Shepard's son, Jesse, remained with the Darks in California, and Dark often accompanied Jesse on visits to his father.
The friendship and letters of Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark are the subject of a documentary by Director Treva Wurmfeld (Shepard and Dark, 2012), and their collection of letters are published by The University of Texas Press in Two Prospectors: The Letters of Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark (2013).
Index Terms
Subjects
Actors; Dramatists -- Texas; Authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century
Document Types
Correspondence
Subjects (Persons)
Shepard, Sam, 1943-2017; Dark, Johnny, 1940-
- Correspondence, 1972-2011
  Series Description
  Series I: Correspondence comprises the bulk of the collection (boxes 1-4) and is arranged chronologically. The first letters are from the early 1970s when the Shepards lived briefly in England and the Darks remained in California. Because the two families lived together for many years, there are few letters until 1980 when Shepard began filming on location. The letters pick up in earnest in 1983 after Shepard left his wife and son and began a long-term relationship with actress Jessica Lange. For the next three decades, the two men kept up a fairly regular correspondence.
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 7 p., October 19, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 7 p. Envelope included, October 28, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 2 p., December 15, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. TL, 3 p. Envelope included, January 20, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. TL, 1 p. Envelope included, January 25, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Scarlett. ALS, 2 p., October 22, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 2 p. Envelope included, October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, October 30, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 3 p. Envelope included, November 4, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard (2 letters), TLS, 4 p. Envelope included, November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard, ALS, 4 p. Envelope included. Enclosed photograph of Shepard and Dark on the hood of a pickup truck, March 25, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard, TL, 2 p. Envelope included, March 25, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 14 p. Envelope included, March 29, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 3 p., April 12, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, April 18, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 5 p., April 29, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard, ALS, 3 p. Envelope included. 3 photocopy pages of The Lost Doctrine of the Soul enclosed, May 24, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, July 13, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 3 p., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 4 p. Envelope included, August 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, September 5,1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, September 6, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 6 p. Envelope included, October 10, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 8 p. Envelope included. Enclosed sections of dialogues: 'Prospector Play,' 'Hotel,' and 'LA." Also enclosed 4 photocopy pages of Memory Babe, a biography of Jack Kerouac., October 31, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 10 p. Envelope included, November 5, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, November 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, December 10, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. 6 photocopy pages of Idiots in Paris enclosed, December 22, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard, ALS, 18 p. Envelope included. 8 photographs enclosed, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included, March 23, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, March 30, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 7 p. Envelope included. 5 photographs enclosed, May 14, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS,1 p. Envelope included. Written on photocopy page containing snapshots of Shepard, Dark, and Jesse Shepard, August 4, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS. 4 p. Envelope included, October 29, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 5 p. Envelope included. Print out of photo of Dark and Shepard enclosed, May 20, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included. 22 typed pages enclosed "Inyo Mountains, California.", August 20, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, December 21, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. 3 photocopies of 1972 letters enclosed [originals in folder 1], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p, June 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, June 1, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, card. Envelope included. Photocopy pictures of Dark enclosed as well as typed pages, "Magic.", November 3, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, October 3, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 8 p. Envelope included, October 11, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, October 29, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p. 5 photographs enclosed, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p. Envelope included. Typed manuscript, "Notebook" enclosed, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark, ALS, 2 p., September 4, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark, ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, May 27, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included. Photo enclosed, September 1, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. 1 p. Note written on a broadside of a Charles Bukowski poem, "the bluebird", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p., January 9, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, March 17, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, February 15, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, September 22, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included., March 10, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. Envelope included, May 13, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard. "Shading up from the first heat of the day easing in through the clouds", August 16, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Shepard letter on reverse, September 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Written on back of Dark letter, September 23, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Shepard letter on reverse, November 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included. Written on back of Dark letter, November 28, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Photocopy pages relating to Kerouac enclosed, January 24, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, March 1, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p.; TL, 1 p. Envelope included. 21 photographs enclosed, July 25, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p., January 13, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard. Envelope included, June 8, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p; TL, 1 p. 3 photographs enclosed, July 15, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included. Photocopy pages of Remembrance of Things Past, August 1, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included, August 20, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, September 22, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., October 6, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, November 7, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, postcard, November 25, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard [Thanksgiving]. TL, 2 p., November 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. Photocopy of ALS, 7 p., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, January 9, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included, January 30, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, February 4, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 5 p. Envelope included, March 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included. Photograph enclosed, March 19, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, June 21, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. Envelope included, June 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 12 p. Envelope included, July 9, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, July 14, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, August 7, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 2 p. Envelope included, August 22, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, September 8, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, January 5, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, January 16, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, February 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, February 7, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, March 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, April 17, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, May 5, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p. Envelope included, June 15, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 4 p. Envelope included. 2 photographs of Jesse Shepard plus a photocopy of his headshot and vita enclosed. Also enclosed, 1 photograph of Shepard and son Walker, and a photo of Walker Shepard, June 18, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, July 27, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, August 20, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, October 14, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p., November 23, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, November 29, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, December 3, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 4 p. Envelope included, January 26, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, January 30, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 2 p. Envelope included, February 6, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 7 p. Envelope included, February 10, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included, February 24, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 4 p. Envelope included, March 28, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 5 p. Envelope included, June 1, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 7 p. Envelope included, August 22, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, November 19, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 7 p. Envelope included, January 1, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p. Envelope included, January 25, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 2 p., February 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, postcard, February 28, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 2 p., August 4, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, September 10, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, September 20, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, November 1, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p., January 21, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 2 p. Envelope included. 4 page typescript of exchange between Dennis and Bill Caryl enclosed, January 23, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 3 p.; ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, January 25, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p., March 18, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, April 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p., May 7, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p. Written on the back of a page from a Dark letter, May 15, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, May 27, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 1 p. Envelope included. 12 typescript pages of Dark's book on The Work enclosed, June 3, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL. 2 p. Envelope included. 2 photos of Jesse Shepard with the Darks enclosed, June 4, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, July 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Shepard response on reverse side, June 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Written on reverse of Dark letter, June 24, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 9 p. Envelope included, July 19, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 1 p., September 21, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p., September 26, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, October 21, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 1 p. Poem "Sixty" enclosed, 2 p., photocopy, November 16, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. "Two Fools at the Crossroad" typescript enclosed, 20 p., November 23, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., January 23, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, February 2, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, card. Envelope included, February 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., April 28, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 7 p. Envelope included. New Yorker review of The God of Hell, by John Lahr enclosed, October 9, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, December 14, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included, March 23, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, April 6, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 14 p. Envelope included, April 8, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 3 p. Envelope included. Photo of Dark enclosed, April 14, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included. Photo of car enclosed, April 14, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included. Typescripts "Today, "60," "Short Poems," "We Do Deliveries!" and "Missed Connections Ad" enclosed, May 24, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 9 p. Envelope included, May 28, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 5 p., August 29, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., January 7, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., February 24, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, May 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS 3 p., June 1, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included, September 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p Envelope included. 4 photocopy images of Dark enclosed., November 10, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., November 14, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p., 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 11 p., June 2, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. TLS, 3 p., June 9, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. Photocopy, 1 p., June 20, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p., August 25, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 15 p., October 8, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, postcard, November 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 5 p., November 5, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p. Written on Village Voice fax w/ Shepard poem in memory of Bill Hart, January 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., March 8, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS. 3 p., May 7, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p., July 17, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., September 24, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p., October 1, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included, January 10, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., January 15, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 4 p. 27 page manuscript enclosed, January 25, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p., February 4, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. 1 p. Photocopy pages: "Emily Bukowski" poem and excerpts from The Friends of Eddie Coyle enclosed, February 4, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 6 p.; TLS, 2 p. Envelope included, February 8-9, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 6 p., February 11, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p., April 28, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 8 p., May 7, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 9 p., August 9, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 4 p. Envelope included, August 20, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 4 p., September 15, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 7 p. Envelope included, October 8, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 10 p. Envelope included, November 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., November 28, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p.; ALS, 1 p. Envelope included, December 11, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 2 p. Envelope included. Photo of Dark enclosed, December 12, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., December 14, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 1 p. "I Don't Know What You're Saying" typescript enclosed, December 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included, January 13, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p. Envelope included, January 26, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p. Envelope included, January 28, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 4 p. Envelope included. Print out page re: Catcher in the Rye enclosed, January 30, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 5 p., February 18, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 1 p. Photo of Dark taken on day of wife Scarlett's death enclosed, February 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. TL, 3 p. Manuscript pages enclosed, February 27, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dark to Shepard. ALS, 5 p. Envelope included. Photocopy letter from October 22, 1976: Shepard to Scarlett, enclosed [original house in folder 1]. Also enclosed 2 p. excerpt from Dark's "Scarlett book.", March 16, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 2 p. Envelope included. Photo of Dark enclosed, July 1, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., July 1, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 2 p., July 2, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., July 9, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 6 p. Envelope included, July 11, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Shepard to Dark. ALS, 3 p., July 16, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dark to Shepard. TLS, 3 p. Envelope included, July 16, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)